<resources>
    <string name="app_name">subbub</string>
    <string name="app_author">Jason Jordan</string>
    <string name="supported_versions">Requires Android TV / Google TV 13 or later</string>
    <string name="help_text">
<![CDATA[
<font color="#FF03DAC5"><b>What is subbub?</b></font><br>
subbub listens to the audio of whatever you are watching and translates it into subtitles in real time in the language you choose. You can place subtitles directly over your screen so you can keep watching while reading.
<br><br>

<font color="#FF03DAC5"><b>Supported Devices</b></font><br>
subbub works on Android TV and Google TV running Android 13, 14 or 15.
<br><br>

<font color="#FF03DAC5"><b>How to Use</b></font><br><br>
<b>1. Choose an audio source</b><br>
&#8226; <b>System Audio</b> — captures sound directly from the TV. Best quality, no background noise.<br>
&#8226; <b>Microphone</b> — uses the device microphone. Can pick up room noise and is less accurate.
<br><br>

<b>2. Choose the Spoken language</b><br>
The language being spoken on screen (for example, English).
<br><br>

<b>3. Choose the Subtitle language</b><br>
The language you want subtitles to appear in (for example, Polish).
<br><br>

<b>Example:</b> Watching an English show and want Polish subtitles? Set <i>Spoken language</i> to English and <i>Subtitle language</i> to Polish.
<br><br>

<b>4. Press Start Subtitles</b><br>
The app will ask for permissions, then subtitles will appear.
<br><br>

<b>5. Stop anytime</b><br>
Pull down the notification shade and tap the <b>Stop</b> button.
<br><br>

<font color="#FF03DAC5"><b>Permissions</b></font><br><br>
<b>Draw over other apps</b><br>
Required so subtitles can appear on top of YouTube, live TV, or any other app. Without this, subtitles only appear inside subbub itself.
<br><br>

<b>Record audio</b><br>
Android requires this even when capturing system audio. Also used as a fallback when system audio capture is not possible.
<br><br>

<b>Capture screen / MediaProjection</b><br>
When using System Audio, Android shows a system dialog asking to allow capture. We use this only for the audio stream, not video recording.
<br><br>

<font color="#FF03DAC5"><b>What Works</b></font><br><br>
&#8226; <b>Free-to-air TV</b> — best case. Broadcast audio is not blocked.<br>
&#8226; <b>YouTube on Android TV</b> — generally allows audio capture.
<br><br>

<font color="#FF03DAC5"><b>What Does Not Work</b></font><br><br>
&#8226; <b>Netflix, Disney+, Spotify</b> — block audio capture for copyright. Switch to Microphone mode or use a second device.<br>
&#8226; <b>Cheap TV sticks</b> — with less than 2 GB RAM may struggle.<br>
&#8226; <b>Some TV overlays</b> — Sony, TCL, Xiaomi, and Fire TV may block third-party overlays when their apps are in focus. Use a second device as a workaround.
<br><br>

<font color="#FF03DAC5"><b>Troubleshooting</b></font><br><br>
<b>Subtitles disappear when switching apps</b><br>
Some Android TV manufacturers block third-party overlays when their launcher or video apps are in focus, even with the Draw over other apps permission granted. This is a system restriction.
<br><br>
Workarounds:<br>
&#8226; Return to subbub periodically to check subtitles.<br>
&#8226; Use a second Android device (phone or tablet) running subbub in Microphone mode, placed near the TV speakers.<br>
&#8226; On some TVs, enabling <i>Developer Options → Disable HW overlays</i> may help.
<br><br>

<b>Subtitles never appear</b><br>
Make sure all three permissions are granted:<br>
&#8226; Draw over other apps<br>
&#8226; Microphone<br>
&#8226; Screen capture (for System Audio mode)<br><br>
If any were denied, go to <i>Settings → Apps → subbub → Permissions</i> and enable them manually.
<br><br>

<font color="#FF03DAC5"><b>Speech & Translation Models</b></font><br><br>
The first time you use a spoken or subtitle language, subbub downloads a small on-device model over Wi-Fi (about 40–50 MB). After that, it works offline.
<br><br>

<font color="#FF03DAC5"><b>Author</b></font><br>
subbub was created by Jason Jordan.
]]>
    </string>
</resources>
